A Guide to the Papers of The Colson-Hill Family
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
- Photographs
  - Photographs- Friends (by name) or school affiliations
    - Lill Kersey (Box-folder 71:51)
    - Anna Laura Lindsay (Box-folder 71:52)
    - Anna Laura Lindsay (Box-folder 71:53)
    - Alphonso and Flossie (Box-folder 71:54)
    - Madden (Box-folder 72:1)
    - Maggie and Willnette (Box-folder 72:2)
    - Amaza Meredith (Box-folder 72:3)
    - Amaza Meredith (Box-folder 72:4)
    - Amaza Meredith (Box-folder 72:5)
    - Amaza Meredith (Box-folder 72:6)
    - "Midget" (Box-folder 72:7)
    - Vilva Moseley (Box-folder 72:8)
    - Essie Overton (Box-folder 72:9)
    - William A. Pantan (Box-folder 72:10)
    - Cinderella Pettiford (Box-folder 72:11)
    - Gilbert Ramsy (Box-folder 72:12)
    - The Ridley's (Box-folder 72:13)
    - Rissia (Box-folder 72:14)
    - Rissia (Box-folder 72:15)
    - Robinson (Box-folder 72:16)
    - A.G. Royal (Box-folder 72:17)
    - Ruth Royal (Box-folder 72:18)
    - Herbert Sharpe (Box-folder 72:19)
    - J.S.C. Stevens (Box-folder 72:20)
    - Henry Tanner (Box-folder 72:21)
    - Dr and Mrs. C. O. Thomas (Box-folder 72:22)
    - Virginia Union University (Box-folder 72:23)
    - T.C. Walker and group (Box-folder 72:24)
    - Walter (Box-folder 72:25)
    - Tossie Whiting (Box-folder 72:26)
    - Addie Berrywood (Box-folder 72:27)
    - Cella (Box-folder 72:28)
    - John Batchuan and H.D. Woodson (Box-folder 72:29)
    - John Batchuan (Box-folder 72:30)
    - Morian Patterson (Box-folder 72:31)
    - Fisk Unidentified (Box-folder 72:32-41)
    - Female-Unidentified (Box-folder 73:1-56)
    - Female Group Unidentified (Box-folder 73:57-65)
    - Male Group Uidentified (Box-folder 73:66-77)
    - Male Group-Unidentified (Box-folder 74:1-29)
    - Male- Unidentified- Jamestown Expository 1907 1907 (Box-folder 74:30)
    - Male-Unidentified, Golfing (Box-folder 74:31)
    - Male Group-Unidentified (Box-folder 74:32)
    - Group-Unidentified (Box-folder 74:33-35)
    - Couple- Unidentified (Box-folder 74:36-37)
    - Child- unidentified (Box-folder 74:38)
    - Couple-Unidentified (Box-folder 74:39)
    - Male-Unidentified (Box-folder 74:40)
    - Couple-unidentified (Box-folder 74:41)
    - Child-Unidentified (Box-folder 74:42-46)
    - Male Unidentified (Box-folder 74:47)
    - Child-Unidentified (Box-folder 74:48-50)
    - Female-Unidentified (Box-folder 74:51)
    - Child-Unidentified (Box-folder 74:52-63)
    - Group-Unidentified (Box-folder 74:64)
    - Child-Unidentified (Box-folder 74:65)
    - Group Children- Unidentified (Box-folder 74:66-70)
    - Family-Unidentified (Box-folder 74:71)
    - Group-Unidentified (Box-folder 74:72-73)
    - Choir- Unidentified (Box-folder 74:74)
    - James Major Colson and Fannie Meade Bolling (Box-folder 75:1)
    - Mr.s Fannie Yovonn (Box-folder 75:2)
    - Miss Maggie Oliver (Box-folder 75:3)
    - Miss Rebecca Barnnister (Box-folder 75:4)
    - Unidentified Photo's (Box-folder 75:5)
    - Negatives (Box-folder 75:6)
    - Photo Book (Box-folder 75)
      Photo Book containing mostly tin-types of friends of the Colson/Hill Family. Most are in color.
- Scrapbooks
  Twelve Scrapbooks generated by Edna Meade Colson. Each book is titled. Most of the books consist of photo's some correspondence, news-clippings and postcards.
  - Memory Books
    - The Hill Line
    - E M C
    - Fisk University
    - Edna Meade Colson
    - Colson 1976
    - V S U
    - Schools
    - Here and There
    - People
    - Press Clips
    - Postal Cards
    - Untitled (Retirement)
- Printed
  - Programs, Invitations, Pamphlets
    - Program Comm, James Major Colson- Dartmouth College 1883 (Box-folder 76:1)
    - Invitation-Wedding Family- Kate Hill 1886 (Box-folder 76:2)
    - Invitation-Wedding Family-Kate Hill 1886 (Box-folder 76:3)
    - Invitation-Evening with Family-W.S 1926 (Box-folder 76:4)
    - Founders Day Invitation Jannie Porter Barrett 1975 (Box-folder 76:5)
    - Invitation-Wedding Family-Kate Reynolds and James Major Colson 1977 (Box-folder 76:6)
    - Colson-Hampton Negro Conference 1902 (Box-folder 76:7)
    - Colson American Negro Academy Minutes Report 1901 (Box-folder 76:8)
    - Programs-Religion, Luncheon (Box-folder 76:9)
    - Edna Colson Photos Group U.D. (Box-folder 76:10)
    - Colson Family Photos Dix (building) Program Fromal Opening 1933 (Box-folder 76:11)
    - The Kiddle Review 1926 (Box-folder 76:12)
    - Negro Achievement (Omega Psi Phi) 1936 (Box-folder 76:13)
    - Verpers 1937,1941 (Box-folder 76:14)
    - Senior Class Day 1933 (Box-folder 76:15)
    - Shepherd Funeral Program 1947 (Box-folder 76:16)
    - Jackson Memorial 1956 (Box-folder 76:17)
    - Artist Recital 1937 (Box-folder 76:18)
    - Jun. Normal Program (ALS) 1926 (Box-folder 76:19)
    - American Education Week 1953 (Box-folder 76:20)
    - Collegiate Debates 1937 (Box-folder 76:21)
    - Jackson-Tinsley Program Dramatic Debate 1956 (Box-folder 76:22)
    - Theatre Guild 1951,1977 (Box-folder 76:23)
    - The Players Guild 1934 (Box-folder 76:24)
    - D. Webster Davis High School Play 1938 (Box-folder 76:25)
    - Voc. and Practical Arts 1969 (Box-folder 76:26)
    - The College Follies 1934 (Box-folder 76:27)
    - Convocation, Summer 1938 (Box-folder 76:28)
    - The VA Statesman 1951 (Box-folder 76:29)
    - Christian Museum Seminar 1955 (Box-folder 76:30)
    - Guide Right Week-Kappa Alpha Psi 1937 (Box-folder 76:31)
    - Founders Day Program 1943,1947 (Box-folder 76:33)
    - School Improvement League 1923 (Box-folder 76:34)
    - Obituaries Funeral Programs (Box-folder 76:35)
    - Institute on Race Relations 1945 (Box-folder 76:36)
    - Annual Consecration of Teachers 1940 (Box-folder 76:37)
    - Lincoln University-Music 1928 (Box-folder 76:38)
    - 63rd Annual Commencement of Peabody High School 1932,1936 (Box-folder 76:39)
    - Henry Williams School Program 1921 (Box-folder 76:40)
    - Sigma Phi Sigma (Box-folder 76:41)
    - Program-E.M.C 1929 (Box-folder 76:42)
    - Rural Community Schools (Box-folder 76:43)
    - Awards 1944,1974 (Box-folder 76:44)
    - Certificate for Courtland Colson 1917 and 1918 (Box-folder 76:45)
    - William N. Colson Certificate 1903,1908 (Box-folder 76:46)
    - Certificate, Golden Report-Peabody Edna Colson 1900,1902 (Box-folder 76:47)
    - Dartmouth Commencement 1906-1908 (Box-folder 76:48)
    - Printed- VSU (Box-folder 76:49)
    - Certificate for James M. Colson V (Box-folder 76:50)
    - National Negro Health Week (Box-folder 76:51)
    - Waterford Public School (Box-folder 76:52)
    - Flyer for Virginia Voters League 1951 (Box-folder 76:53)
    - Halifax County Band Rally 1944 (Box-folder 76:54)
    - Cumberland County Mass Meeting 1945 (Box-folder 76:55)
    - Flyer for the Tobacco Bowl Classic 1945 (Box-folder 76:56)
    - Announcement 1884 (Box-folder 76:57)
    - Scottsboro Boys 1932 (Box-folder 76:58)
    - A lecture on "Caste" 1885 (Box-folder 76:59)
    - Political Cartoon (Amsterdam News) (Box-folder 76:60)
    - Schedule of Examinations 1887 (Box-folder 76:61)
    - Newspaper Clippings 1892 (Box-folder 76:62)
    - Prairie View College (Box-folder 76:63)
    - Newsletter James M. Colson Retires (Box-folder 77:1)
    - The Southern Patriot 1945 and 1946 (Box-folder 77:2)
    - St. Pauls 1950 (Box-folder 77:3)
    - Birth Control Review 1919 (Box-folder 77:4)
    - The Southern Frontier 1945 (Box-folder 77:5)
    - The Woman's Press 1922 (Box-folder 77:6)
    - Progress Record 1939 (Box-folder 77:7)
    - United Civic League of New York (Box-folder 77:8)
    - AMEZ- Newsletter 1942 (Box-folder 77:9)
    - Fisk News 1917 (Box-folder 77:10)
    - African Stories for Children (Box-folder 77:11)
    - Art and Color line (Box-folder 77:12)
    - VSU Alumni Newsletter (Box-folder 77:13)
    - The Southern Frontier (Box-folder 77:14)
    - Virginia Teachers Association (Box-folder 77:15)
    - Newsletter (Box-folder 77:16)
    - VSU Newsletter (Box-folder 77:17)
    - Newsletter Peabody 1941 (Box-folder 77:18)
    - School Improvement and Beautition Plans (Box-folder 77:19)
    - High School Torch Newsletter 1937,1940 (Box-folder 77:20)
    - Jackson Memorial 1956 (Box-folder 77:21)
    - Wedding Invitation (Box-folder 78:1)
    - YMCA (Box-folder 78:2)
    - Farewell Banquet- Co. 1-17th Provisional (Box-folder 78:3)
    - Dartmouth (Box-folder 78:4)
    - Wedding Invitations-Family (Box-folder 78:5)
    - Eaton Family School (Box-folder 78:6)
    - Va. Building and Savings Association 1882 (Box-folder 78:7)
    - Certificate for Courtlandt Colson 1917 and 1918 (Box-folder 78:8)
    - 4-H (Box-folder 78:9)
    - Fisk (Box-folder 78:10)
    - Certificate for James Major Colson V 1946 (Box-folder 78:11)
    - Chesterfield Co. School Exhibit (Box-folder 78:12)
    - Letter-Invitation 1914 (Box-folder 78:13)
    - Alpha Delta Phi 1882 (Box-folder 78:14)
    - Certificate for Kate Colson 1874-1875 (Box-folder 78:15)
    - Joseph Jenkins Program (Box-folder 78:16)
    - Va. Union (Box-folder 78:17)
    - Columbia University (Box-folder 78:18)
    - Class Day- Dartmouth 1883 (Box-folder 78:19)
    - John M. Langston Banquet 1886 (Box-folder 78:20)
    - White Cross League- Fisk 1913 (Box-folder 78:21)
    - Henry Author Callis- Alpha Phi Alpha (Box-folder 78:22)
    - James M. Colson retires (Box-folder 78:23)
    - Fisk University- Normal Department 1908 (Box-folder 78:24)
    - O.P Hare and Co. 1896 (Box-folder 78:25)
    - Program- Richmond Co. High School 1940 (Box-folder 78:26)
    - Petersburg Public Schools 1900-1902 (Box-folder 78:27)
    - Vesper Program- Sigma Delta Omega Club 1932 (Box-folder 78:28)
    - Botetourt County Exhibit 1926 (Box-folder 78:29)
    - Commencement Invitation 1910 (Box-folder 78:30)
    - Commencement Program 1905 (Box-folder 78:31)
    - AMEZ- Newsletter 1942 (Box-folder 78:32)
    - Building Dedication- Colson Hall- Winston Salem 1952 (Box-folder 78:33)
    - Winston Salem 1915,1971 (Box-folder 78:34)
    - Certificate for William Nelson Colson 1903 (Box-folder 78:35)
    - Peoples Building and Loan Association 1889 (Box-folder 78:36)
    - State of Virginia (Box-folder 78:37)
    - Hampton Negro Conference 1902 (Box-folder 78:38)
    - Womens Day Program 1941 (Box-folder 78:39)
    - Virginia State University (Box-folder 78:40)
    - Program 1934 (Box-folder 78:41)
    - Programs (Box-folder 78:42)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 78:43)
    - Newspaper Clippings 1892 (Box-folder 78A:1)
    - Hampton 1886-1909 (Box-folder 78A:2)
    - Invitation- Booker T. Washington (Box-folder 78A:3)
    - John A. Dix 1905 (Box-folder 78A:4)
    - Schedule of Examinations 1887 (Box-folder 78A:5)
    - Hon. John Mercer Langston-His Call and His Commission 1885 (Box-folder 78A:6)
    - Memo (Box-folder 78A:7)
    - Howard University 1915 (Box-folder 78A:8)
    - Invitation- Class of 1925 (Box-folder 78A:9)
    - Graduating Exercises 1912 (Box-folder 78A:10)
    - Ticket to Lecture Dec. 1894-Apr 1895 (Box-folder 78A:11)
    - Hartshorn Memorial College 1908 (Box-folder 78A:12)
    - William Nelson Colson Certificate 1908 (Box-folder 78A:13)
    - Dartmouth 1906-1908 (Box-folder 78A:14)
    - St.Pauls 1905 (Box-folder 78A:15)
    - Peabody High School 1936 (Box-folder 78A:16)
    - The Virginia State Teachers Association 1915 and 1934 (Box-folder 78A:17)
    - Julius Rosenwald 1932 and 1934 (Box-folder 78A:18)
    - Shepard 1942 (Box-folder 78A:19)
    - The Southern Patriot 1946 (Box-folder 78A:20)
    - The Southern Frontier 1945 (Box-folder 78A:21)
    - The Womens Press 1922 (Box-folder 78A:22)
    - Brith Control Review 1919 (Box-folder 78A:23)
    - VSU 1956 (Box-folder 78A:24)
    - Programs 1937 (Box-folder 78A:25)
    - Programs (Box-folder 78A:26)
    - Programs (Box-folder 78A:27)
    - Programs (Box-folder 78A:28)
    - Programs (Box-folder 78A:29)
    - Printed (Box-folder 78A:30)
    - Printed Programs (Box-folder 78A:31)
    - American Negro Academy (Box-folder 78A:32)
    - VSU Alumni Newsletter (Box-folder 78A:33)
    - A Lecture on "Caste" 1885 (Box-folder 78A:34)
    - Invitation-From the Institute for Colored Youth (Page 79)
    - Invitation-Fisk U. Commencement 1908 (Page 79)
    - Invitation- Fisk Commencement 1915 (Page 79)
    - Invitation- Fisk Commencement 1915 (Page 79)
    - Program-Fisk Commencement 1908 (Page 79)
    - Program- Fisk Anniversary 1915 (Page 79)
    - Program- Music Festival VS College for Negroes 4/21/1933 (Page 79)
    - Program- Music Festival VS College for Negroes 4/22/1933 (Page 79)
    - Program- Virginia State High School Commencement 1934 (Page 79)
    - Program- Virginia State College Baccalaureate Services 1934 (Page 79)
    - Program- 4th District Teachers Association Annual Meeting 1959 (Page 79)
    - Program- Virginia Commission on Interracial Cooperation 1933 (Page 79)
    - Program- Musical Recitals The George F. Bragg Home for Boys 1945 (Page 79)
    - Program- Banquet Honoring Dr. John L. Lockett 1962 (Page 79)
    - Program- Annual Banquet, Gamma Chapter of Alpha Phi Alpha 1914 (Page 79)
    - Program- A Luncheon Honoring Mrs. Cleopatra Armstrong 1917 (Page 79)
    - Program- Rosenwald's Day Celebration- VSC 1933 (Page 79)
    - "Experiment Station" Tuskegee N and II Bulletin #1 - Feeding Acorns 1898 (Page 79)
    - "Experiment Station" Tuskegee N and II #3- Fertilizer Experiments on Cotton 1899 (Page 79)
    - "The V N and II Gazette" 1909 (Folio 79)
    - Pamphlet- The Electoral Vote of 1896 (Page 79)
    - "The Progressive Nature Studies" by G.W. Carver 1897 (Page 79)
    - "Teh Child and the Curriculum" by John Dewey (Page 79)
    - "The Truth about Columbia Tennessee Cases" (Page 79)
    - "Preliminary List of Books and Pamphlets by Negro Authors" (Page 79)
    - Weekly Calender of the Community Church of New York 1/17/1926 (Page 79)
    - Weekly Calender of the Community Church of New York 1/23/1926 (Page 79)
    - Program-Funeral Services for Ruth Taylor Baker (Page 79)
    - Program-Memorial Service for Thomas Howard Henderson (Page 79)
    - Program- Funeral Services for Rev. Thomas Langston Puryear (Page 79)
    - Bulletin of Information-Winston Salem Teachers College 1925 (Page 79)
    - Special Circular- Winston Salem Teachers College (2) 1925 (Page 79)
    - Valentine Card 1952 (Page 79)
  - Dartmouth Alumni Association
    - Freshman History- Class of 1883 (2) (Page 80)
    - Sophomore Class History-Dartmouth College (Page 80)
    - Dartmouth College Catalogue 1882-1883 (Page 80)
    - Senior History-Class of 1883 (2) (Page 80)
    - First Annual Report Class of 1883 1884 (Page 80)
    - Second Annual Report Class of 1883 1885 (Page 80)
    - Dartmouth Alumni Association 1886 (Page 80)
    - Sixth Annual Report Class of 1883 1889 (Page 80)
    - Phi Beta Kappa Catalogue 1887 (Page 80)
    - Report of the Class of 1883 1893 (Page 80)
    - Dartmouth College:The Relation of the College and Schools 1893 (Page 80)
    - Report Class of 1883 1899 (Page 80)
    - Report Class of 1883 April 1899-July 1902 (Page 80)
    - Report Class of 1883 1908 (Page 80)
    - Alpha Beta Phi Chpater Letter and Alumni list 1908 (Page 80)
    - "The Crater Scroll" Feb 1925 (Page 80)
    - "The Crater Scroll" May 1925 (Page 80)
    - Annual Report- School Board of the City of Petersburg 1890-1891 (Page 80)
  - Degrees
    - James Major Colson III. Middleborough High School 1879 (Folder 10)
    - James Major Colson- Dartmouth, A.B 1883 (Folder 10)
    - William Nelson Colson-Wayland College of Virginia Union University A.B 1914 (Folder 10)
    - William Nelson Colson- Columbia University Bachelor of Laws 1922 (Folder 10)
    - William Nelson Colson- Hampton 1908 (Folder 10)
    - James Major Colson- Dinwiddie A and I June 6 1923 (Folder 10)
    - Myra Hill (Colson) Harthorne Womens College 1908 (Folder 10)
    - Edna Meade Colson- Fisk Normal 1908 (Folder 10)
    - Edna Meade Colson- Fisk BE (Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings
    2 boxes loose news clipping from a number of newspapers from around the United States no order or no arrangement